尽管把宝宝从医院带回家是件幸福的事
As great as it is bringing a baby home from the hospital,
有种声音绝对是你醒来时恐惧面对的
there's one sound you absolutely dread waking up to...
亲戚们
Relatives.
我还真没见过这些婚礼照片 妈妈
I really never saw these wedding pictures, mamá.
爸爸看起来多年轻潇洒啊
How handsome and young papa looks.
看得我好伤感
Ay, it makes me sad.
我知道你想念他
Ay, I know that you miss him.
不是 你看我的翘臀
No. Look at my ass.
照片里有两样东西 现在我都失去了
There are two things in that picture I don't have anymore.
妈妈 您太搞笑了
Ay, mama, que loca.
桑娅 需要我帮忙吗
Sonia, can I help you?
没事 没事 让她忙去吧
No, no, she's fine. It keeps her busy.
得再来点玉米 歌洛莉亚 菜园在哪
We need more corn. Gloria, where is your garden?
我去摘点儿
I will harvest some.
宝贝儿 城里人家里可没菜园
They don't live that way, honey.
歌洛莉亚 给我车钥匙 我们去趟超市
Gloria, give me the keys. We'll go to the market.
嘿 你们都起床啦 我都没听见你们的动静
Hey, you're all awake. I didn't hear you.
看看我们家两个帅哥
Oh, look at my two handsome men.
我的宝贝 我的小弗汉希欧·翁贝托
Mi nio, my little Fulgencio Umberto.
说到名字 我们还没完全确定...
You know, about the name, we're not entirely sure...
桑娅 走啦 再见哟 弗汉希欧
Sonia, vámonos. Good-bye, Fulgencio.
跟弗汉希欧再见
Say good-bye to Fulgencio.
再见 弗汉希欧
Good-bye, Fulgencio.
他的名字叫乔
His name is Joe.
你去告诉她我们不会用她去世的老公
You tell her that we're not naming him
或他爹的名字给孩子取名
after her dead husband or his father before him.
-他的名字是 -别说了
- His name was-- - Please don't say it again.
杰 我不能违背我妈妈的愿望
Jay, I cannot go against my mother's will.
但她喜欢你
But she likes you.
如果你去劝她
Maybe if you convince her...
弗汉希欧·翁贝托--缩写是F.U.普里契特
Fulgencio Umberto-- the initials are F.U. Pritchett,
我现在就是这种操蛋的感觉
which is exactly the way it feels right now.
教父教母有什么着装要求吗
Is there some kind of dress code for godparents?
不许戴你那顶大傻帽子 菲尔
You're not wearing a fedora, Phil.
你能去取下干洗的衣服吗
Can you pick up the dry cleaning?
听起来我好像不能拒绝啊
That sounds like an offer I can't refuse.
别 我们不搞这一套
Yeah, we're not doing that.
我接莉莉下舞蹈课已经迟到了
So I got delayed picking up Lily from dance class.
现在歌洛莉亚又叫我到处跑
Now Gloria's got me running around
准备一堆洗礼的事
doing a thousand things for christening.
操他妈的
Son of a bitch.
别激动 我只是发发牢骚而已
It's not that bad, really. I'm just--I'm venting.
难以置信 有人把气球
I couldn't believe it. Somebody's balloons
挡到我的广告牌了 菲尔牌
were blocking my billboard. Philboard.
我的菲尔牌
My Philboard.
我们能把穿去参加洗礼的衣服
Can we wear the same outfits at Crispin's party
穿到克里斯宾的派对上吗
that we're wearing to the baptism?
这个啊 我也不知道
Oh, you know what? I don't know.
因为你想在教堂低调
Because you wanna be subdued at church
到了晚上却很华丽
and then fabulous at night.
你知道谁会狠赚一笔吗
You know who would make a fortune?
给男人设计小黑裙的设计师
The designer who comes up with the little black dress for men.
我好无聊
I'm bored.
我知道 小甜心 但是爸爸们在讨论
I know, sweetie, but daddies are talking
我们晚上要穿什么
about what we're gonna wear tonight,
那可是很难做决定的
and that's a difficult conversation.
-难死了也跟本小姐无关 -莉莉
- Cry me a river. - Lily.
我不喜欢你这样哦
I-I'm not loving this attitude.
你这样显得有点刻薄
You seem a little mean.
对不起 需要我帮你们叫辆"救父车"吗
Sorry. Should I call you a wah-mbulance?
我的天啊 她最近好毒舌啊
Oh, my gosh. She has been so snarky lately.
是啊 现在只要一害她迟到
I know. I've actually been getting nervous
我的神经就很紧张
when we're making her late for something.
因为她那天说的话吗
Because of what she said the other day?
-"抓紧时间 小姐们" -真伤人
- "Today, ladies." - Hurtful.
你也知道 她听到我们那样说话
You know, she hears us doing it,
所以我们 我们不该造成那么多负面影响
So we--we should try and be less negative.
做好榜样
Model some better behavior.
是啊 如果她需要的是一名模特
Yeah. Well, you know, if it's a model she needs,
那她就来对地方了
She's come to the right place.
-妈呀 -哼
- Oh, boy. - Hmm.
要是莉莉在就好了
I wish Lily was in here,
她就可以看到我对这事不予置评
so she could hear me not comment on that.
知道啦 你在扮模特走秀
I get it. You're modeling.
嘿 又是我 菲尔·邓菲
Hey, it's Phil Dunphy again.
你的电话断线了
I-I got cut off by your machine.
不知道刚刚说到哪了
I'm, uh, not sure where I left off there,
但我尽量长话短说
but I'll attempt to be brief,
因为别人这么做我也会很感激
As I do appreciate when people do the same for me.
话说回来 你的气球挡住--妈的
Anyhoo, uh, your balloons are co--damn it!
有人在家吗 妈
Is anyone home? Mom!
我先找她的 妈
I need her first. Mom!
她出去了
She's out.
我们需要一个成年人的时候她怎么老不在
Why is she always gone when we need an adult?
-我可以帮忙 -盒子里是什么
- I can help. - What's with the cage?
-科研项目 -妈 你在哪里
- Science project. - Mom, where are you?
-出去了 就我们三个在 -四个
- Out. It's just the three of us. - Four.
-我需要她 -是老鼠
- I need her. - Rats.
我知道 好吧
I know, right?
同志们 我就在这里 你们需要什么
Guys, I'm right here. What do you need?
没事 我们没事
No, it's okay. We're good.
-没事 -不 不不不不不
- Okay, never mind. - No. No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
家庭会议 每人抓块披萨
Family meeting. Everybody grab some 'za.
一起讨论下这个问题
We're gonna talk about this.
听着 我知道你们喜欢找妈妈
Listen, I know you guys like to go to mom,
因为她是问题解决小能手
because she's Mr.Tough guy problem-solver.
她办事有结果
She gets results.
对 她有 她有 你没错
Yeah, she does. She does. You're right.
比如上次 我们买到了最喜欢吃的披萨
Like the last time we got pizza from our favorite place here.
还记得那次吗 他们少找了我们零钱
Remember that? We got shortchanged,
她连珠炮似的骂了一通 把钱要回来了
She cursed a blue streak and got our money back?
顺便问下 披萨好吃吗
How's that pizza, by the way?
-挺好的 不错 -撒谎
- Pretty good. It's okay. - Liars!
难吃死了
It's garbage.
那不是斯卡迪诺家的披萨 是斯卡多尼的
That's not Scardino's, it's Scandoni's.
你们知道为什么吗
You know why?
因为你们老妈的小脾气得罪他家了
'cause your mom's little blow-up
我们这辈子都吃不到斯卡迪诺家的披萨了
got us banned from Scardino's for life.
所以 也许老妈的办法并非总是最好的
So maybe your mom's way isn't always the best way.
现在 你们跟我说说发生什么事了
Now why don't you guys tell me what's going on?
我本来打算下周办一场60年代主题生日派对
I'm having a '60s-themed birthday party next week.
嬉皮士 喇叭裤 扎染什么的
Hippies, bell-bottoms, tie-dye.
凯伦·苏利文知道了
Karen Sullivan heard about it,
决定办一场同样的派对 就在今晚
and decided to have the same party... tonight.
情况不妙
Not groovy.
我一不留神把我"老师"叫成了"老妈"
I accidentally called my teacher "Mommy".
我"朋友"罗本到处宣传 全校都知道了
My "Friend" Reuben went around and told everyone.
我说 罗本
Oh, hey, Reuben,
你还记不记得那次全班到动物园郊游
do you remember that class field trip to the zoo
有只斑马从栅栏里冲出来 你都尿裤子了
when the zebra rushed the fence and you peed your pants?
我都没告诉任何人 就算他在坐车回家的时候
I didn't tell anyone, not even on the bus ride home
不得不坐在老妈旁边...
when he had to sit next to mom--
不对 是鲍克曼老师 该死
Ms. Bockman! Damn it!
我们邻居出远门了
Our neighbor's out of town,
所以她雇我在街道清扫日那天替她挪车
and she's paying me to move her car on street cleaning days.
我倒想只是把车停在车道上
Now I would just park it in her driveway,
可那里已经停了一台露营车 还种了很多树
but she already has a camper and a cord of wood there.
她肯定是女同性恋
Pretty sure she's a lesbian.
不管怎么说 这钱容易挣 对吧
Anyway, easy money, right?
我的神呐 我什么也看不见
Oh, my god, I can't see anything!
右满舵
Hard starboard!
那是什么意思啊
What does that even mean?!
我还要在这里堵人堵多久啊
How much longer do I have to block people?
我赶飞机要迟到了
I'm late for the airport.
迪兰 你现在一点忙都没帮上
Dylan, you are being no help right now!
对不起 但是我自己也遇到"分流"麻烦
Sorry, but I'm already in trouble with dispatch
我之前喝太多水了
for drinking all those little waters.
开车 快开
Drive! Do it now!
我要怎么告诉她 她心爱的柠檬树
How do I tell her I snapped a branch
树枝被我撞折了
on her beloved lemon tree?
那些叶子她是要煮来
I mean, she boils the leaves
给她自制的靴子油添加香味的
to add a scent to her own work boot oil.
我有没有提到她效力于两个垒球联盟
Did I mention she plays in two softball leagues?
你们这些家伙要怎么办
Now what are you guys gonna do?
你们是希望让你们老妈四处转转
You gonna have your mom go around
跟这些人大喊一通 毁坏一批友谊的桥梁
and yell at all these people and burn a bunch of bridges?
还是 去和你们的罗本们
Or are you gonna talk to your Reubens,
凯伦们 还有你的柠檬...女士谈谈
your Karens, your lemon... lady,
和他们谈谈你们的感受
tell 'em how you feel,
唤起他们人性的一面
appeal to their human side?
这选择显而易见 对吧
The choice is pretty simple, huh?
就是说她今天不会回来了
So she's out all day?
-我再试试打她的手机吧 -关机了
- I'll try her cell. - It's off.
老爸说话的时候我给她发短信了
I texted her while dad was talking.
皮娜 我给你带了杯咖啡
Pilar, I brought you a coffee.
我往里面加了点儿料
Oh. I put a little something extra in it.
杰 你耍坏
Jay, you devil.
顺便说一下 你看
Hey, by the way, look...
漂亮不
it's beautiful, no?
这是为弗汉希欧洗礼准备的袍子哦
It's the dressing gown for Fulgencio's christening.
我们家所有男丁都穿过它
All the men in our family wear this.
不会又给我来个基佬儿子吧
What's one more son in a dress?
这是传统 那可是很重要的
Oh, tradition. Oh, it's so important.
我为小弗汉希欧准备了一个礼物 放在这里
I have a gift in here for little Fulgencio.
这东西在我们家族里传了三代人了
That has been in my family for three generations.
关于给孩子起名的事情
You know, about this naming thing--
在美国 福建西欧这个名字可真不常见
In America, it's not real common to hear the name Fuljencio.
应该是"弗-汉-希欧"
It's "Ful-hen-cio."
-汗 -汉
- Hen? - Hen.
我不用练这个 我不会给我儿子起这名字的
I don't need to practice it 'cause I can't name my son that.
我只是和你实话实说
I'm just being honest with you.
不 没关系 这样很好
No. No, no, no, no, that's good.
这样很好 有时候我也该和你说说实话
That's good. I should be more honest with you sometimes.
是啊 我们彼此相识也有些年头了
Well, we've known each other a few years.
我不喜欢你 杰
I don't like you, Jay.
我们可以看在家庭的份上 装作一切都好
nah. We can act like everything is fine for the family,
但是 你知道的 我从来没喜欢过你
But, you know, I have never liked you.
你那种见到好东西就要占的嘴脸
The way you take whatever looks good to you--
比如 我女儿或者最后一块肉
you know, like my daughter or the last piece of meat.
你总是很忙 忙到不能去机场接我
You're always too busy to pick me up at the airport.
只派来一个完全陌生的人举块纸牌子
You send a total stranger with a cardboard sign.
-嗨 外婆 -你好
- Hi, grandma. - Hey.
伙计 到这儿来
Hey, buddy. Get over here.
我是真的很喜欢你送我的十字架
I sure do love the cross you got me.
可是我今天必须带着它吗
But do I have to wear it today?
我的衬衫都因此扣不上了
It's kinda hard to close my shirt over it.
不 不用
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
你想怎么样都行
You do whatever you want, Padrecito.
我知道这个家里就是这种行事风格
I know that's the way in this house.
不过你要是带上它 会让我非常骄傲的
But if you wear it, ooh, you'll make me proud.
那已经在我们家族里传了五代人了
It's been in my family for five generations.
-好吧 -我送你出去 小弟
- Okay. I'll walk you out, buddy.
她家里有没有什么东西是新的
Is anything in her family new?
就是你呗
Just you.
好的 让一让 不好意思
Okay. Excuse me. Sorry.
好了 我们有熏腌大拼盘了
All right. Here we've got the deli platter,
我车里还有更多
and there's more in my car.
但这些不是从兰伯努克家买的
But those are not from Rumpernook's.
没错 因为我得罪他们家...
No, because the cheese at Rump...
因为我再也不去他家买了
I don't go there anymore.
我去洗衣服了
I'm going to do the laundry.
好的 桑娅 好爱你哦
Okay, Sonia. I love you so much.
你对这新管家挺有爱的哈
Wow. Pretty cozy with the new housekeeper, huh?
她是我妹妹
She's my sister.
哇 你这么使唤你妹妹啊
Wow. Pretty weird with your sister.
她喜欢忙前忙后 但我挺同情她的
She likes to keep busy. But I feel bad for her.
我拥有这么多 她却一无所有
I have so much, and she has nothing.
好吧 人们选择自己的命运
Okay. Well, people make their own choices.
你不需要为此负责
It's not like you're responsible.
不 不是的
No, no.
好像还是有一点
Maybe just a little bit.
我比较年长 有机会出去旅行
I was older and I had opportunities to travel,
我就抓住一切机会
and I took them.
那也不会阻止她去任何地方啊
Well, it didn't prevent her from going anywhere.
不不不
No, no.
只是有一次
Maybe just one time.
有一封来自美国的信
There was a letter that arrived from America
提供了一个工作机会
about a job opportunity.
但只有一人能去
And it was only for one person,
于是我就去了
And I went.
但那又不是写给她的信
But it's not like the envelope was addressed to her,
你偷偷打开 然后
And you opened it and...
你太坏了
you're evil.
我必须离开那里 克莱尔
I had to get out of there, Claire.
你蹬上了高跟鞋
You just strapped on those high heels
踩着她的背走过去 不是吗
and walked right over her back, didn't you?
好像是
Maybe a little bit.
哪儿有小溪给我洗衣服
Where is the river?
嘿 二位帅哥
Hey, boys!
克里斯宾
Crispin.
你不是应该在准备
Hey, shouldn't you be preparing
你们的世纪大年会吗
for your annual party of the century?
已经收工了 非常完美
It's done and it's perfect.
我都已经开始策划明年的了
In my mind, I'm already into next year's.
听着 我和布雷特一起来的
Listen, I'm here with Brett.
不知道你们有没有看过他的新造型
I don't know if you've seen his new look,
但你们肯定要被吓得心脏病发作而死的
But you are going to have a heart attack and die.
没人会死的
No one's dying.
-只是一种表达方式 -没错
- It's just an expression. - Yeah.
帅哥你好啊
Hey, handsome.
没错 我做到了
Yep, I did it.
下定决心 烫了个头
Pulled the trigger and got a perm.
你还真去做了
You sure did.
我自己在厨房里做的
Did it myself, right in the kitchen.
哥不需要花大价钱
You don't need to spend a million
就能弄出大价钱的效果
to look like a million.
我的咖啡应该快好了
Uh, you know, my coffee's probably ready, so...
再见
Bye.
他就跟个草头娃娃似的 对吧
Okay, that's like a chia pet, right?
或许是异装癖版的"安妮"[百老汇剧目]
Maybe a drag production of "Annie"?
其实嘛 莉莉
Oh, actually, Lily,
我 我想克里斯宾叔叔忘了
I-I think Uncle Crispin's forgetting
布雷特也是会伤心的
that Brett has feelings,
所以我们应该努力不去伤害
and we need to try and not hurt them.
对 也许我们该提醒克里斯宾叔叔
Yes, and maybe we should remind Uncle Crispin
只有当你对人们友好时
that when you say nice things to people,
他们才会对你友好
they say nice things back.
好吧 多谢提醒
Well... Consider me reminded.
得赶紧走了
Gotta run.
好的 今晚见 再见
Yeah, we'll see you tonight. Bye.
好的 迫不及待 迫不及待
Okay. Yeah, can't wait. Can't wait.
他真有趣
He's funny.
是啊 但有时候也很伤人[咬人]
Yes, he is, but he can also be biting.
-他会咬人吗 -当然是用他的话语
- He bites people? - Well, with his words,
不是像美术班的山德那样用牙齿咬
Not with his teeth like Xander from art class.
我们得确认他有没有打疫苗
We need to confirm he got his shot.
好的
Yeah.
我的天呐 克里斯宾说
Oh, my god. Okay, Crispin--
"太多人报名了 不得不减少参加人数
"Too many rsvps. Have to make cuts to party.
下次再请你们吧" 伤心脸
Maybe next time." Sad face.
因为我们拒绝侮辱别人
Because we refuse to abuse,
他就禁止我们参加世纪大派对
we get banned from the party of the century?
二位父亲大人需要"救父车"吗
Does somebody need a wah-mbulance?
不用 我不需要什么"救父车"
No.I do not need a wah-mbulance.
孩子们好啊 今天过得怎么样
Hey, kids. How was your day?
我心里早有答案
I knew the answer to that question.
我今天挺忙的
I'd had kind of a busy day
四处奔波 解决各种问题
going around solving everyone's problems.
我先去了我邻居斯塔夫罗斯的花店
I started by going to see my buddy Stavros the florist.
你是斯塔夫罗斯 对吧
Stavros, I assume?
有事吗
Yes?
我是来欢迎你成为我们的邻居
I just wanted to welcome you to the neighborhood.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
对了 我还给你带了点三明治
Yeah, I brought you some sandwiches, by the way.
羊羔肉相当不错哦
How good is lamb, huh?
-尼克斯 -我接住你了
- Nikos! - Oh! Gotcha.
快回屋去
Get back in there.
真不好意思
I'm so sorry.
有什么能为你效劳的吗
Is there anything I can do for you?
没有 没有 我
Oh, no. No. I...
当时我突然意识到我的孩子们还不理解
That's when I realized my kids didn't understand
以德"伏"人的意思
the concept of killing with kindness
因为他们从未亲眼见过
because they'd never seen it.
于是我决定证明给他们看
So I decided I'd prove it to them
看我怎么以德"伏"人
by going on a huggacidal rampage.
那不是戴着哈利·波特眼镜的罗本嘛
Is that Reuben rockin' the Potter specs?
魁地大奇葩
Quiddiculous!
听我说 哥们
Hey, listen, buddy,
我听说了卢克叫他老师"妈咪"的事
I heard about Luke calling his teacher "Mommy."
的确是史上最囧啊
Epic fail, by the way.
但是 既然你是学校里受欢迎的孩子
But, you know, since you're one of the cool kids,
也许你能劝劝其他孩子别取笑他了好吗
maybe you could get the other ones to ease off a little?
好 隔空对个拳
Cool. Air bump.
你好 李 我是住在街尾的菲尔·邓菲
Hey, Lee, it's Phil Dunphy from down the street.
我们没见过面 我打给你其实是
We haven't met. I was actually calling
想给你老婆留个言
to leave a message for your wife,
感谢她雇我女儿海莉做事
just to say thanks for hiring my daughter Haley.
我们想请你和你太太过来喝杯酒
Listen, we'd love to have you and the missus over for a glass of wine,
或者我们两个爷们可以一起出去喝两杯
or--or, uh, maybe you and I could go out for a boys' night.
总之 如果你可以...
But anyway, if you could--
该死
Damn it!
你好凯伦·苏利文 我是艾丽克斯的父亲
Hey, Karen Sullivan. Alex's dad.
看看谁把牙齿整得如此洁白又整齐啊
Well, look whose teeth got so nice and straight.
谁先说
Who wants to go first?
-你开什么玩笑 -你疯了吗
- Are you kidding? - Are you crazy?
你到底想干什么
What are you trying to--
一个一个说
One at a time!
你称呼库珀小姐为一个男人
You called Ms. Cooper a man!
不 我没有啊
No, I didn't.
-答录机上是她老公李 -她没老公
- I got her husband Lee on the machine. - There is no husband!
她就是李
She's Lee!
声音异常低沉的同性恋酒鬼李·库珀
Weirdly deep-voiced, alcoholic, gay Lee Cooper
而你却邀请她去喝酒
who you invited out for a glass of wine!
感谢你迷人地冒犯了凯伦
Thanks to your little charm offensive with Karen,
她的派对内容的确改变了一点
one thing did change about her party--
就是将我除名了
I'm not invited!
"魁地大奇葩" "史上最囧"
"Quiddiculous"? "Epic fail"?
现在整个学校在取笑我们父子俩了
Now the whole school is just laughing at both of us.
斯塔夫罗斯 你好
Stavros, hey!
为什么不行
Why not?!
干什么
What?
计划有变
Change of plans.
这事儿还没完
This isn't over.
我想让你今晚打扮得漂漂亮亮
I want you to wear something beautiful tonight.
尽管挑吧
So please, choose.
这屋子是干什么用的
What is this room?
这是衣帽间
This is the closet.
那镇上所有的居民
So all the people of the town,
都把漂亮衣服寄存在你这里吗
they leave their nice clothes with you?
不 这些都是我的衣服
No. These are all my clothes.
但是 我其实很怀念家乡的简朴风俗
But... I do miss the simple things at home.
跟我说说 村子里都还好吗
So tell me, how-- how are things in the village?
家乡发洪水了
We had a flood.
但不是特别严重 对吧
Ay, but it--it wasn't a bad one, right?
我们曾有条船
We had a boat.
那就好
Ay, that's great.
是"曾经"有条船
We had a boat.
你有对象了吗
Are you dating anyone?
你记得安东尼奥·马奎斯吗
You remember Antonio Marquez?
当然记得
Yes, of course.
学校里的校草
The most handsome boy in the school
有一双迷人的眼睛
with those beautiful eyes.
我在和他的瘸腿老爹谈恋爱
His father with the wooden leg...
洪水把他的木腿冲走了
He lost it in the flood.
你俩是认真的吗
So is it serious?
别看
Don't look at that.
我不会看的 相信我
I won't. Trust me.
他们太贱了
Please. It's pathetic.
克里斯宾让所有闺蜜给我们发短信
Crispin's been getting all of our friends
报告他那盛大派对的各种细节
to text us the details of his great party.
折磨死人了 是吧
Such torture, huh?
餐饮由阿米莉亚餐厅提供
Oh, catering by Amelia's.
上身赤裸的泊车员
Topless valet parkers.
-斯汀[糟透了] -就是啊
- Sting. - Exactly.
不是 我是说斯汀也在派对上
No, Sting is at the party.
米奇尔 人家真的好想去
Mitchell, I wanna be there.
-小卡 -不 拜托
- Cam. - No, come on.
别自欺欺人了 你也想去的
Who are we kidding? You do, too.
抓紧时间啊 小姐们
Today, ladies!
听好了 就是这句
Okay, right there. That.
正因为这个我们必须要做出牺牲
That is why we are making the sacrifice--
为了我们的闺女
For our daughter.
是啊 你说得对
Oh, yeah, you're right.
我最没资格抱怨了
I mean, I'm the last one who should be complaining
毕竟 面对现实吧
when, let's face it,
莉莉变成毒舌妇是我的过错
Lily's snarkiness is my doing.
木已成舟
Well, what's done is done.
快打扮整齐出发去教堂吧
Let's just get ready for church.
是啊 只是很难不感到惭愧
Yeah, I mean, it's just hard to not feel guilty,
毕竟大部分是由我造成的
you know, when it's mostly my fault.
我理解 别太自责了
I get it. Just don't beat yourself up.
要带手帕吗 还是不带比较好呢
Hey. Pocket square? No pocket square?
真的吗 你觉得自己一点责任都没有吗
Really? You're taking zero of the responsibility, or...
你想把这事怪到我身上来吗
Oh. Were you trying to get me to take the blame?
也许有一点
Maybe just a little.
然后剥夺你做烈士的机会吗
Oh, and deny you the chance to play the martyr?
听着 小卡 你要是想让我来当罪人
Look, Cam, if you're looking for me to be the bad guy,
你找错对象了 懂吗
you're snarking up the wrong tree, okay?
你才是那个遇事不吐槽
You are the one who can't let a single situation pass
就不罢休的人
without making a comment.
也许我可以从今开始改变
Oh, well, maybe I'll just start today.
我想那样会让你开心些的
I think it'll make you feel better.
我已经感到开心了
I think I already do.
她当着我的面就说 "我不喜欢你"
Right to my face, "I don't like you."
没有人不喜欢我
Nobody doesn't like me.
我是杰 人见人爱的杰
I'm Jay. I'm-- I'm salt of the earth.
你为什么拼命闻我的孩子
Why are you inhaling my baby?
他们只会好闻一段时间
Oh, they only smell perfect like this for a little while.
就是这味
Yeah. That's the stuff.
从第一天开始 我就把她当女王来对待
From day one, I've treated this woman like a queen.
我处处围着她转
I've flown her back and forth,
我还尝了她的土特产
I've... I've tasted her native food.
你知道下巴是什么味吗
You know what chin tastes like?
我可知道
Mm. 'cause I do.
现在我发现
And now to find out...
怎么了 我听着呢
What? I'm listening.
你在用婴儿蹭自己
You're rubbing yourself with the baby.
我还看过你和你的狗湿吻呢
I have seen you french kiss your dog.
她在我嘴里找食物
She was taking a treat out of my mouth.
那是个训狗技巧
That's a trick.
我敢肯定你知道
I am sure you know
我觉得这件事有趣在哪
what I find funny about this situation.
在哪
What?
你有一个无论你多么努力
You have an in-law who, no matter what you do,
也没法讨好的丈母娘
No matter how hard you try, you can't win over.
那怎么了
What about it?
等等 听着不耳熟吗
Wait. That doesn't sound familiar?
你不是说
You're not saying...
我是的
Yeah, I am.
擦 我成菲尔了
Son of a bitch, I'm Phil.
皮娜 天太冷了
Hey, Pilar, it's awfully cold.
你穿我的外套吧
Here. Why don't you take my jacket?
真行 让我显得没礼貌是吧
Sure, yeah. Make me the rude one.
很抱歉我指出了
Look, I'm sorry that I pointed out
我们两个都应该受责备 好吗
that we're both to blame here, all right?
但是我们不要把这么美好的事
But let's not turn this lovely event
变成竞争好吗 穿我的 亲爱的
into a competition. Here you go, sweetie.
你说得对 我不应该挑你毛病
Oh, you know what? You're right. I shouldn't be picking at you.
但是别忘了去点燃你的蜡烛
But don't forget to light your candle.
我看所有直系亲属都点了
I think everyone in the immediate family's doing it.
好的 好主意
Oh, yeah? Okay. Good--good idea.
那是什么玩意
What the hell is that?
同性恋抗议什么的吗
Some kind of gay protest thing?
是蜡烛 爸 你说什么呢
It's a candle, dad. What are you talking about?
你的紫色裤衩尾巴
You' purple panty tail.
不是吧
Oh, no. Oh, come on.
我们是在教堂里 不是在夜店
We're in church, Mitchell, not some disco.
你故意的
You did that on purpose!
教堂的彩色玻璃真美
Oh, this stained glass is beautiful.
在为孩子洗礼之前
Now listen, before we dunk the kid,
我能简单说两句吗
You mind if I make a few casual remarks?
我以为你已经说了呢
I think you already did.
克莱尔问了我一个很好的问题
Claire asked me a good question--
菲尔是怎么讨得我欢心的
How did Phil win me over?
好吧 他还没有
Well, he hasn't yet.
但是 当他不再刻意讨好的时候
But when he stops trying so hard,
像个正常人一样 就离目标近一些了
and he acts like a real person, he comes close.
我就应该这么对皮娜
That's what I needed to do with Pilar.
我想告诉你们
I'd like to tell you the story
我是怎么遇见我可爱的妻子的
of how I came to meet my incredible wife,
因为 除了这个孩子的降临
Because up until the birth of this child,
那是我一生中最美的事
It's the best thing that ever happened to me.
这话听起来真"舒服"
Mm, that feels good huh?
一天早上 我的汽车送去打蜡了
So it's morning. My car's getting waxed.
我吃了个午饭
I hop in the diner.
我听见了一个可爱的口音
I hear this adorable accent.
我转过身 看见一个美女正和她朋友说话
I turn. I see this pretty girl talking to her friend.
我送过去一个派
I send over a piece of pie.
真经典
All class.
几分钟过后
Couple of minutes later,
歌洛莉亚过来谢谢我
who comes over to thank me but Gloria,
她是我见过的最美丽的女人
the most beautiful woman I've ever seen.
阿门
Amen.
她坐下 我们开始聊天
She sits down, we start talking,
从此我们就再也没停过
And we haven't stopped talking since.
但是疯狂的是
But here's the crazy part--
我不是给歌洛莉亚送的派
I didn't send the pie to Gloria.
她背对着我
Her back was to me.
我是送给她朋友的
I sent it to her friend,
但是她去厕所了就错过了
who went to the bathroom and missed it.
那个人今天也在场
And that person is here today--
她就是歌洛莉亚的妹妹桑娅
Gloria's sister Sonia.
真有趣 生命中一个小小的改变
Isn't it funny how a simple twist of fate
就可以改变一个人的命运
can change the whole--
你偷了我的生活
You stole my life!
等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait. Hold on, hold on.
我抓住桑娅了
I got Sonia!
别说了 我要我的生活 我的床
No more. I want my own life, my own bed,
还有我的电子邮箱
my own e-mail account!
是啊 抛弃你的亲娘吧
Yeah, leave your poor old mother alone.
别担心 妈妈 你可以跟我们一起住
Don't worry, mama. You can come and live with us.
等等 想清楚再说
Whoa. Pump the brakes here.
怎么了 你对我妈有意见吗
What? Do you have a problem with my mother?
不是 是你妈对我有意见
No. Your mother has a problem with me.
你认为她很无助 你问问她盒子里的是什么
You think she's helpless. Ask her what's in that box.
不是我们家祖传的枪吗
It's not the family gun?
杰 如果歌洛莉亚有什么不测
Jay, if anything should happen to Gloria,
我随时补上
I am there for you.
什么 桑娅 我会有什么不测
What, Sonia? What's going to happen to me?
你可能有一天走进你的衣帽间
You might go for a walk in your closet one day
然后一去不复返
And never come back!
知道自己错过什么了吧
See what you're missing? Huh?
卢克在哪里
Where is Luke?
站在马修旁的就是他啊
I think he's the one standing next to Matthew.
菲尔
Phil.
他心情不太好
He was feeling a little under the weather.
我让他待在家里了
I let him stay home.
也许他是觉得太丢人 不好意思出门
Or is he just too embarrassed to leave the house?
他为什么会觉得丢人
Why would he be embarrassed?
因为老爸想帮忙解决我们的问题
Because dad tried to fix all our problems,
却帮了倒忙 毁了我们的人生
and instead, ruined all our lives.
恶梦一场
Nightmare.
你们这些小姑娘太夸张了
You girls are so dramatic.
需要我给你们叫辆"救父车"吗
Do I need to call you a wah-mbulance?
-你听到了吗 -当然
- Did you hear that? - Yes!
这周都是克莱尔送莉莉去上舞蹈课
Claire's been driving Lily to dance class all week.
莉莉全是跟她学的
That's where she gets it from!
我们为人父母不算失败 失败的是克莱尔
We're not bad parents. Claire is.
我说过我不会哭的
I said I wasn't gonna cry,
但是 老天爷 眼泪止不住哗哗的
but, oh, boy, here it comes.
不 小卡 别用这个
No, no, Cam. Not with those.
好啦 别吵了
Okay! That's it!
我们现在是在神的教堂 他妈的
We're in a house of god, damn it.
行啊 所有人都弃我而去吧
Fine. Everyone just abandon me.
皮娜 无意冒犯
Pilar, all due respect,
你装可怜这套没人会信的
no one's buying the martyr act.
连这家伙都不会信
Not even this guy.
你一直将桑娅留在自己身边
You ask me, you've been keeping this one under your thumb
是因为你害怕继续你的人生
'cause you're afraid of going on with your life.
但你是位迷人的女性 魅力无限
But you're an attractive woman with a lot to offer.
那或许就是个大大的机会
This could be an opportunity.
我直到60岁时才明白幸福的含义
I don't even think I knew what happiness was till I was 60.
打击还在继续 走吧
And the hits just keep coming. Okay.
桑娅 我们会帮你找到自己的一片天地
Sonia, we're gonna help you get your own place,
帮助你独立
have some independence.
如果你感到孤单
And if you ever get lonely,
你随时想来看我们都行
you come visit us as much as you want...
在合理的范围内
With--within reason.
-我们也会让这小家伙去看你 -什么
- And we'll send this one down to visit you. - What?
但他不会当神父的 因为这家伙好色
But he's not gonna become a priest 'cause he likes girls.
追不到女生 可是非常喜欢
Can't get 'em, but he likes 'em.
所以 大家好好想想
So... Everybody think about it.
别想太久
But not for too long.
这儿六点还要办戒酒互助会呢
There's an A.A. Meeting here at 6:00.
桑娅 拜托 让我们帮你吧
Sonia, please, let us do this for you.
我真的希望你开心
I really want you to be happy.
你能原谅我吗
Can you forgive me?
需要花些时间
It will take some time.
花多长时间都行
As much as you need.
还要加上些衣服
And some dresses.
要多少都行
As many as you want.
还要加上些鞋子
And some shoes.
你现在说的是气话
You're angry now.
无论你和孩子们之间发生了什么事
Whatever happened with the kids,
我不希望你心里不好受
I don't want you to feel bad about it.
我没有
I don't.
现在请教父教母上来
I now invite The godfather and the godmother to join us.
别担心
Don't worry.
明天我会搞定一切的
I will take care of everything tomorrow.
也许没这个必要了 我的爱妻
That may not be necessary, my wife.
菲尔与克莱尔 作为教父母
Phil and Claire, as godparents,
你们准备好帮助
Are you ready to help
孩子的父母完成他们的职责了吗
the parents of this child in their duties?
-准备好了 -准备好了
- We are. - We are.
你愿意弃绝恶魔吗
Do you renounce satan?
-我愿意 -我愿意
- I do renounce him. - I do renounce him.
以及他的所有罪行吗
And all his works?
我愿意抛弃
I do renounce them.
抛弃他所有虚空的承诺吗
And all his empty promises?
我的天啊
Oh, my god!
我愿意抛弃
I do renounce them.
教父 你希望这孩子受洗吗
Godfather, is it your wish that this child be baptized?
希望
It is.
以圣父圣子圣灵之名
In the name of the father and the son and the holy spirit,
你们给这孩子取什么名字
what name have you given the child?
弗汉希欧·乔瑟夫·普里契特
Fulgencio Joseph Pritchett.
愿上帝保佑诸位
May god be with you all.
谢谢你 杰
Thank you, Jay.
我们永远不会这样叫他
We're never gonna call him that.
我听说那天有人
So I heard that somebody
在凯伦·苏利文的派对上放了一群老鼠
released a bunch of rats into Karen Sullivan's party the other night.
李·库珀的露营车撞倒了她的柠檬树
And Lee Cooper's camper just rolled into her lemon tree.
卢克在学校也没有麻烦了
Luke isn't having any problem at school anymore,
因为罗本在学校承认 整件事是他编的
because Reuben admitted he made the whole thing up.
是不是很疯狂
Isn't that crazy,
孩子们的麻烦全都解决了
how all our of kids' problems just disappeared?
永远别过问我的事 克莱尔
Don't ever ask me about my business, Claire.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
别过问我的事
Don't ask me about my business.
我没有
I wasn't.
很好
Good.
别问
Don't.